

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







CSM, CSPO, Engineering Program Manager seeking roles in Agile Program Management, Product Development, Engineering management, Project Management, DBM, Customer Delivery

Management, SAFe, Agile, C/C++/Java/VC++, Oracle/MySQL/SQL Server, SQL, JSON, HTML, Python

Total Experience: 18 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Designation: Program Manager

Current Company: CATechnologies, ABroadcom company Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: MCA[Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance Role: Program Mar

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Engineering Program Manager, Agile Program Management, Product Development Manager, Project

Management, Databases, Customer Delivery

Management, SAFe, Agile, C, C++, Java, VC++, Oracle, MySQL, SQL, PL/SQL, JSON, Python, Scrum Master, Scrum, Program

Management,PMO

Verified : L Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Certified program manager with experience in Agile Program management, scrum master activities, customer delivery management for SaaS(GCP/AWS) & on-prem solutions.

Product development & application development experience in C/C++, Java and Web technologies. Functional experience includes Analytics, Databases, Networking, Telecom Customer Care

Core skills include SAFe, Agile, C/C++, Java, VC++ with MFC/Win32, Database technologies like Oracle, DB2, MYSQL, MS SQL server and Sybase.

Well versed with agile methodology, highly organized and hand-on in running agile ceremonies like PI planning, Sprint planning/retrospectives, system demos, Inspect and Adopt workshops. Expert in managing expectations with customer success team, presales and field.

Work Experience

- CA Technologies, A Broadcom company as Program Manager Apr 2004 to Till Date
 - 18 years of overall experience with 8 years of experience on to Scrum master and program manager activities
 - Well versed with different flavors of Agile: Scrum, Scaled Agile Framework, Kanban etc
 - Excellent experience of working with a cross-functional teams in planning a product releases, managing impediments and dependencies for team
 - Served 6 scrum teams including the distributed teams. Guided scrum masters on agile best practices and to become high performant by grooming and mentoring
 - Leading events: Excellence in agile methodology running ceremonies like PI planning, sprint planning, retrospectives, system demos, DSM, inspect and adopt workshops
 - Proficient in Agile Metrics(burndown, velocity, burnup), Maturity assessments for teams and also coached other scrum masters in identifying the anti patterns, gaps and areas of improvements
- Excellence in implementing Agile Best Practices such as time-boxing, continuous integration, code/design reviews, transparency, product vision, technical debt reduction, promoting self-organized teams, empowerment and role training resulting in realized velocity improvement
- Set up and enforced standard software best practices and deliverables (including defect management and quality metrics reports) within the gated process to streamline Testing & release activities and SaaS rollout pipeline.
- Managed cross-functional collaboration with engineering, product management, i18n/l10n, platform, documentation, system testing, VPAT, DevOps & SaaSOps and presales teams
- Help teams continuously reflect and improve, becoming more effective in their roles and increasing their predictability, collaboration, and quality practices
- Experience in driving engineering practices (Coding Standards, TDD, Test Automation, Continuous Integration, Refactoring, Pair Programming, etc.)
- Negotiates scope changes with the Product Owner Team based on Sprint results
- Expertise in coaching teams become self-organizing, high performant by exhibiting Scrum Values. Help scrum



Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

masters in identifying anti patterns, work on them and become high performant

- * Lead the Agile Community of Practice from India center which dealt with Agile Adoption to the new teams, Agile transformation, Key Initiatives and Best Practices that helped in organizational agility across the organization.
- * Technical experience in C/C++, Java, VC++ with MFC/Win32, Database technologies like Oracle, DB2, MYSQL, MS SQL server and Sybase
- Tech Mahindra as Software Engineer

Aug 2002 to Mar 2004

Project -4 SMART

(August 2002 to Mar2004)

Client: - British Telecom Plc. (BT), UK

SMART is an intelligent GUI based front-end to BTs legacy CSS mainframe. BT is using this system throughout UK to gather customer's requirements and information through telephone calls, which enables BT to have a flexible, scalable, and efficient customer service. BT is using this system in phase-by-phase manner enhancing it as per customer's requirement. The project involves the maintenance of 32 modules of the system and making enhancements to them. This requires detailed study of the system and analysis and design and implementation of new requirements. Role: - Developer

Coding in VC++ with MFC with back-end Oracle and CSS mainframe and middle ware MMBI.

Software Estimation using FP analysis

Accessing CSS mainframe using Attachmate's Extra

Using Broker Based Architecture

System modeling using Rational Rose98 and Version control using PVCS.

Requirements analysis, HLD & LLD, Unit testing and Integration testing. Documentation for requirement, solution and testing

Modules Handled: - Repairs, Provisional appointment, Change customer details, Arthur letters, Direct debit

^ Back to Top

Education

PG: MCA (Computers) from National Institute of Technology (NIT), Calicut in 2000

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
C, C++, VC++			
MFC/Win32, Core Java			
Oracle 9i/10g			
DB2 UDB 10			
MS SQL Server 2008			
MySQL 5.x, Sybase			
SQL, PL/SQL, XML			
JSON, HTML, Python			
Microsoft Excel			
MS Project			
Confluence, Git, Spectrum			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
Telugu	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Malayalam	Beginner			✓
Marathi	Beginner			✓

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.